

# **Kingsley Raspe**

### Full Stack Developer / DevOps Engineer

#### CONTACT

(cellphone removed)
hello@kingsley.sh
kingsley.sh
github.com/kingsloi
linkedin.com/in/kingsleyraspe

British Nationality
US Green Card Holder

#### **SKILLS**

Node.js, Laravel, Vue.js, Nuxt.js AWS (S3, SES, EC2, LB, RDS) Serverless (Lambda) CI/CD High Availability Babel/Webpack/Transpiling PHPUnit/Cypress

#### **LANGUAGES**

Javascript (ES6+)

PHP

HTML5/HTML

SCSS/CSS

Bash/Shell Scripting

Linux

Git/GitLab

MySQL, MongoDB

#### **PROFILE**

A full stack web developer and DevOps engineer with 10+ years experience, specialising in open-source tech, specifically Node.js (Express.js), PHP (Laravel), and JavaScript (Vue.js). Passionate about writing highly available, clean, maintainable, and testable code. Originally from the UK, now residing in the beautiful lake-side city of Gary, Indiana.

#### **WORK HISTORY**

#### Founder/President

Sterling Strong Foundation | August 2021 - Present

In honour of my daughter Sterling, our foundation's goals are to raise awareness to/be advocates of congenital heart disease, rare/chronic diseases, and help children and their families during their ICU stays.

### Full Stack Developer / DevOps Engineer (Systems Support Analyst)

Pearson (remote, USA) | May 2017 - Present

- Remotely support an entire fleet of AWS infrastructure, including debugging, management, deployment, securing, upgrading, monitoring & performance updates for ~50 websites.
- Write bespoke code/applications in a variety of programming languages to aid users/developers, their work flows, removing unnecessary bloat/debt, and ensuring processes are as streamlined as possible.

Recent projects include:

- Complete form/lead generation web app & API (Laravel/GitLab CI&CD/ES6/CDN/S3/SES/HAProxy/PHPUnit)
- Bespoke Puppeteer prerender/static HTML service (Node.js/Express.js/Puppeteer/Lambda/SQS/Cypress)



# **Kingsley Raspe**

## Full Stack Developer / DevOps Engineer

#### CONTACT

(cellphone removed)
hello@kingsley.sh
kingsley.sh
github.com/kingsloi
linkedin.com/in/kingsleyraspe

British Nationality
US Green Card Holder

#### **SKILLS**

AWS (S3, SES, EC2, LB, RDS)
Serverless (Lambda)
CI/CD
High Availability
Babel/Webpack/Transpiling
PHPUnit/Cypress

Node.js, Laravel, Vue.js, Nuxt.js

#### **LANGUAGES**

Javascript (ES6+)

PHP

HTML5/HTML

SCSS/CSS

Bash/Shell Scripting

Linux

Git/GitLab

MySQL, MongoDB

#### **WORK HISTORY**

#### **Director / Full Stack Developer / DevOps Engineer**

Forwardslash Consulting Ltd (remote, UK) | January 2014 - May 2017

Worked as a digital nomad, freelancing through Forwardslash Consulting Ltd in the UK and operated as full stack web developer contractor, working with clients around the world, including the USA, Dubai, Australia, and Europe.

#### **eLearning Consultant / Web Developer**

Phones4u (Stafford, UK) | July 2013 - August 2014

Developed a series of internal micro sites/applications to help Phones 4u's 5000 retail staff digest daily/weekly/monthly content from leadership, partners, new tech, regulatory info, etc.

#### Web Developer Intern

The Grossbauer Group (Indiana, USA) | August 2011 - August 2012

12 month international internship as front/backend developer.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **Discover American Sign Language (ASL)**

Indiana University Northwest | 2022 - Present

#### BSc (Hons) International Web Development - Grade 2:1

Staffordshire University, Stafford (UK) | 2010 - 2013

#### **HND Applied Information Technology**

Staffordshire University, Lichfield (UK) | 2008 - 2010

#### **BTEC National Diploma in Applied Information Technology**

Tamworth and Lichfield College, Tamworth (UK) | 2006 - 2008